Weston Rose

1781 Spyglass Dr. #242, Austin, TX | (979) 777-9021 |

weston.rose86@gmail.com GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Skilled web development specialist with six years of experience working in content management systems like Drupal and Wordpress. Adaptable, collaborative, and self-directed problem-solver. Ten years of experience in higher education, communications, and administration. Currently serve as Program & Communications Coordinator at The University of Texas System Administration for the last four years. Life-long learner and former educator. Proficient in Google Analytics, SEO meta-description and keyphrases (Yoast), creating surveys in SurveyMonkey and data visualization, as well as the Adobe Creative Suite.

TECHNICAL SKILLS & PROJECTS

Languages & Frameworks

MERN stack, Python, HTML 5, JavaScript, CSS, jQuery, MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Heroku, GitHub, User Authentication, Testing, Reactstrap, Bootstrap, Bulma, markdown

Projects

- Weston Rose's Company Directory: An employee directory built with React and a
 mock JSON data generated via https://mocokaroo.com. This app allows users to view
 non-sensitive data for all employees in a given company. Users can sort by first and
 last names in alphabetical and reverse-alphabetical order. Users can filter the list of
 employees by last name.
 - o Link: https://wrose001.github.io/employee-directory
- **Budget Tracker:** This budget tracker app allows users to add expenses and deposits either online or offline. Transactions that occur offline are populated when the app is brought back online. A standalone manifest allows users to save to their smartphone home screen as an app.
 - o Link: https://budget-tracker-wr.herokuapp.com/
- Zelda's Cutthroat Kitchen: Served as a backend developer on a team of four, using an Agile project management approach, to produce this eCommerce restaurant app that allows users to select meals and proceed to checkout where they enter credit card information using Stripe. Built with node.js, express, MySQL, Sequelize, HTML, Bootstrap & CSS.
 - o **Link:** https://zelda-cut-throat-kitchen.herokuapp.com/

WORK EXPERIENCE

Program & Communications Coordinator
The University of Texas System Administration

Media & Communications Specialist
Graduate Studies - Sam Houston State University

Lecturer & Academic Advisor
Sam Houston State University

Jun. 2016 – Present
Austin, TX

Aug. 2013 – Jan. 2016
Huntsville, TX

Aug. 2010 – Aug. 2013
Huntsville, TX

EDUCATION

Certificate of Completion: Full-Stack Web Development
The University of Texas at Austin Coding BootcampDec. 2019 – May 2020
Austin, TXMaster of Arts in English Language & Literature
Sam Houston State UniversityJan. 2008 – Aug. 2010
Huntsville, TXBachelor of Arts in English Language & Literature
Sam Houston State UniversityAug. 2005 – Dec. 2007
Huntsville, TX

Other Certificates

- Certificate of Completion: Visual Design (Dec. 2019) from General Assembly. A two month course in UX/UI design covering communication design topics including layout, color theory, and typography, Gestalt principles, user experience, and responsive design. Gained hands-on experience in Adobe XD
- Strategic Communication Certificate (Aug. 2019) from UT Austin's Center for Professional Development. A five-class certificate covering the following topics: Crisis Communications, Data Science, Storytelling, and Audience-Driven Narratives, and Interacting with the Media
- Certificate of Leader Development (Aug. 2018) from UT System Administration.
 Attended an internal summer-long leadership development workshop at my organization that included modules in management style assessment, public speaking, and project management.